<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tomasz Pałucki</title>
    <link>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tomasz Pałucki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 19:27:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A few words on how this blog is built</title>
      <link>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/how-this-blog-is-built/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 19:27:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/how-this-blog-is-built/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any experience in building a blog yet but as an engineer I had some vision and principles I wanted to follow. Some of them are:
 Simplicity and minimalism Readability Ease of configuration Themes available - because I want to deliver fast to stay in the fun zone Possibility to extend later (comments etc)  The easiest way would be to setup blog on a Wordpress powered hosting but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like fun to me 😁 I&amp;rsquo;ve done some research and found out that static site generator would be the perfect solution here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disqus - you&#39;re doing it the wrong way</title>
      <link>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/disqus-the-wrong-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 23:16:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/disqus-the-wrong-way/</guid>
      <description>Recently I started searching for a comment system I could use on this blog. Pretty standard functionality for a blog, but as this is static site, there is no option/plugin included by default.
After some time spent on research I ended up with Disqus - I know there is a ton of hate over this platform recently but honestly installation is super easy - needs just copy-pasting some html/js code, generating id and you are set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Questions</title>
      <link>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/interview-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 22:52:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/interview-questions/</guid>
      <description>Here is the selection of the interview questions that caught me unguarded, so I noted them not to forget
 What is an object&amp;rsquo;s hash code if hashCode() is not overridden? How to achieve object&amp;rsquo;s immutability?  Design patterns:
 Decorator  Data structures:
 Binary tree  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot With Angular build integration</title>
      <link>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/spring-boot-with-angular-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 15:09:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/spring-boot-with-angular-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Angular and Spring Boot are pretty widely used technologies nowadays. Both projects are mature, well documented and supported by large community. That is why I decided to show you how to build self contained Angular 8 application backed with the Spring Boot 2 App.
Code shown in this tutorial might be used as starter template for your own project. All the code is available on my github.
Step 1 - Generate the Spring Boot App Go to https://start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi everyone!</title>
      <link>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 14:54:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tpalucki.github.io/posts/about-me/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post ever so I just wanted to say hello to everyone visiting my page. My name is Tomasz and I&amp;rsquo;ve created this blog to have easily accessible place to post the notes I create during my work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
